靈異第六感
天氣轉涼了
It's gettin' cold.
這個框真不錯
That is one fine frame.
真是個不錯的框
One fine frame that is.
你覺得...
How much...
這麽高級的框值多少錢
Does a fine frame like that cost, do you think?
我沒跟你說過 你喝醉時真像蘇斯博士
I never told you, but you sound a little like Dr. Seuss when you're drunk.
安娜 我是說真的
I know. I'm serious.
我很認真哦
Serious, I am.
我猜最少也要幾百塊錢
I'd say it cost at least a couple hundred.
- 我要宣讀一下 - 我真的像蘇斯博士?
- I'm gonna read it for you. - Do I really sound like Dr. Seuss?
茲表揚他在兒童心理學界
"In recognition of his outstanding achievement...
- 不凡的成就 - 嗯嗯
- "in the field of child psychology, - Mm-hmm.
與熱忱的工作態度以及他持續努力地幫助...
His dedication to his work and his continuing efforts to improve the quality of life..."
專心一點 好嗎?
Will you concentrate?
他持續努力地幫助...
"...his continuing efforts to improve the quality of life...
無數兒童及其家人
"for countless children and their families,
市府很榮幸頒予費城之子
"the city of Philadelphia proudly bestows upon its son...
馬爾科姆·克勞醫生 就是你
Dr. Malcolm Crowe..." That's you...
特等專業優良獎狀
"...the Mayor's Citation for professional excellence."
他們稱你費城之子呢
They called you their son.
天呐
Wow.
我們該把這挂到廁所去
We should hang it in the bathroom.
今晚對我們很重要
This is an important night for us.
終于有人了解你所做的犧牲
Finally, someone is recognizing the sacrifices you've made...
你將一切置于其次 包括我
that you have put everything second, including me,
只爲了這些兒童的福祉
for those families that they're talking about.
這也證明我丈夫很有天份
They're also saying that my husband has a gift.
你教孩子如何堅強面對...
You have a gift that teaches children...
連大人都受不了的處境
how to be strong in situations... Where most adults would piss on themselves.
我相信這些話是真的
I believe what they wrote is real.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我想用酒杯喝酒
I would like some wine in a glass.
我不想用馬克杯
I would not like it in a mug.
也不想用啤酒杯
I would not like it in a jug.
馬爾科姆
Look.
安娜 別動 別出聲
Anna, don't move. Don't make a sound.
這裏是洛克斯街47號
This is 47 Locus Street.
你闖入了私人住宅
You've broken a window and entered a private residence.
你什麽也不知道
You don't know so many things.
這裏沒有毒品或藥物
There are no needles or prescription drugs of any kind in this house.
人獨處時爲什麽會害怕?
Do you know why you're afraid when you're alone?
我知道
I do. I do.
你要幹嘛?
What do you want?
他答應過我 我要他做到
What he promised me! I want what he promised me.
- 我的天 - 我認識你嗎?
- Oh, my God. - Do I know you?
神醫 你不認得我了?
Don't you know me, hero?
你不記得自己的病人?
Don't you even remember your own patients?
市區診所
Downtown clinic.
單親家庭
Single-parent family.
可能患有情緒失調症
Possible mood disorder.
我那時好害怕
I was afraid!
你說我無法面對我父母離婚
You told me I was having trouble coping with my parents'divorce.
你錯了 你錯了
You were wrong. You were wrong.
現在看看我
Now look at me!
- 我不想再感到害怕 - 等我想一下
- I don't want to be afraid no more. - Just give me a minute to think.
我等你十年了
I waited ten years for you!
我不會再等了
I'm not giving you nothin'!
班·費肯?
Ben Friedkin?
有些人叫我怪胎
Some people, they call me "freak."
朗諾·桑尼?
Ryan Sumner?
我的確是個怪胎 看看我
I am. I am a freak. Look at...
文森
Vincent.
文森·格瑞
Vincent Gray.
不 你沒有
No, you don't.
我當然記得你
I do remember you.
安靜 聰明
Quiet, very smart.
有同情心
Compassionate.
非常有同情心
Unusually compassionate.
你忘了我也受到詛咒
You forgot cursed.
你放棄我
You failed me.
你放棄了我!
You failed me!
文森 很抱歉我... 沒幫到你
Vincent, I'm sorry if I wasn't... if I didn't help you.
讓我再試一下
But if you just let me try,
如果你能再給我一次機會
if you just give me a chance...
上帝啊
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- 文森 - 別說話
- Did Vincent... - Don't talk. Shh.
"次年秋天"
"南費城"
"文森·格瑞:十歲"
"科爾·希爾:九歲"
"父母離異"
"極度焦慮 個性孤僻"
"可能患有情緒失調症"
科爾 別怕
It's okay, Cole.
我是馬爾科姆·克勞醫生
My name is Dr. Malcolm Crowe.
我們今天本來要見面的 但是... 我沒趕到
We were supposed to meet today, but I missed our appointment.
對不起
I'm sorry.
在很久以前的歐洲 人們會躲進教堂
You know, in the olden days in Europe, people used to hide out in churches.
尋求庇護
They would claim sanctuary.
他們在躲什麽?
What were they hiding from?
大多是在躲壞人
Bad people, mostly.
那些想把他們關進監獄 傷害他們的壞人
People that wanted to put them in jail, hurt them.
我注意到你的眼鏡 上面並沒有鏡片
I noticed your eyeglasses. They don't have any lenses in them.
這是我爸的
They're my dad's.
有鏡片不舒服
The lenses hurt my eyes.
你剛才跟玩具兵說什麽?
What were you talking about with your soldiers when I came in? Day...
在深淵中，我呼喚你，我的上帝！(拉丁語)
De profundus clamo adite domine
那是拉丁文
It's called "Latin."
- 它們都說拉丁文嗎? - 沒有
- All your soldiers speak Latin? - No.
只有一個
Just one.
你是好醫生嗎?
Are you a good doctor?
是的
Well,
以前是
I used to be.
我得過一張獎狀 市長頒給我的
I won an award once from the mayor.
它的框很貴
It had an expensive frame.
我會再見到你 對吧?
I'm gonna see you again, right?
若你不介意的話
If that's okay with you.
我回來了
It's me.
"拉丁文字典"
"神啊 我自深淵向你哭喊"
早安
Hey, good morning.
科爾
Cole.
Cole!
你的巧克力脆片都軟掉了
Hey, your Cocoa Puffs are gettin' soggy.
讓我看看 寶貝 這兒有汙點
Let me see you. Oh, honey, you got a spot. Head up.
可以了 終于好了
Okay, here we go.
你在找什麽嗎?
Something you were looking for, baby?
夾心餡餅
Pop Tarts?
就在這兒
They're right here.
媽咪 你在想什麽?
Well, what are you thinking, Mama?
很多事
Lots of things.
你覺得我很壞嗎?
Anything bad about me?
嗨 看著我
Hey, look at my face.
我絕對不會覺得你很壞
I was not thinking something bad about you.
明白嗎?
Got it?
明白
Got it.
擡起頭
Here, head up.
- 湯米來了 - 好了 領帶塞進去 科爾
- That's Tommy. - That's okay. You tuck it in.
你要這個嗎?
Cole, you want this?
怪胎 搭肩膀那招如何?
Hey, freak, how'd you like that "arm around the shoulder" bit?
我臨時想的 我真有天份
I just made that up. I went with it.
一流的演員都會 這叫即興表演
It's what great actors do. It's called "improv."
寶貝
Hey, baby.
今天過得好嗎?
How was your day?
恩
Hmm?
你想說什麽就說
You know, you can tell me things if you need to.
你知道我今天做什麽了嗎?
Well, you know what I did today?
我...一早就贏了賓州彩券
I, uh, I won the Pennsylvania Lottery in the morning,
我辭掉了工作
I quit my jobs,
接著到公園去 吃了好多巧克力慕斯派
and I ate a big picnic in the park with lots of chocolate mousse pie.
下午還在噴泉裏遊泳
And then I swam in the fountain all afternoon.
你做了什麽?
What'd you do?
下課後我被選爲棒球隊的第一選手
I was picked first for kick ball teams at recess.
我打了支滿壘全壘打
I hit a grand slam to win the game.
同學把我擡起來大聲歡呼
Everybody lifted me up on their shoulders and carried me around, cheering.
真不錯 我替你煎三角形松餅
Well, in that case, I am gonna make you some triangle pancakes.
一個鍾頭就好
You got an hour.
嗨
Hi.
想坐嗎?
Wanna sit?
今天不想談嗎?
Don't feel like talking today?
想玩遊戲嗎?
Wanna play a game?
這是個猜謎遊戲
It's a mind-reading game.
是這樣玩的
Here's how it works.
我猜你在想什麽
I read your mind.
我說對了 你就往前走一步
If what I say is right, you take one step towards the chair.
如果我說錯 你就往後一步退到門口
If what I say is wrong, you take one step back... towards the doorway.
若你走到椅子旁就得坐下
If you reach the chair, you sit down.
若你退到門口就可以走
If you reach the door, you can go.
想玩嗎?
Wanna play?
好
Okay.
你父母剛離婚時
When your mother and father were first divorced,
你媽媽找過我這種醫生 他幫不了她
your mom went to see a doctor like me, and he didn't help her.
所以你覺得我也幫不了你
So you think I'm not going to be able to help you.
你很擔心 她說她跟醫生說了一些事
You're worried that she said she told him things...
一些她沒跟別人說的事
things she couldn't tell anyone else.
一些秘密
Secrets.
你也有不想告訴我的秘密
You have a secret, but you don't want to tell me.
你父親走之前把那只表留給你
Your dad gave you that watch as a present just before he went away.
他把它忘在抽屜裏了
He forgot it in a drawer.
它壞了
Doesn't work.
你在學校很安靜 但...
You keep pretty quiet in school, but...
你是好學生 從不闖禍
you're a good student, you've never really been in any serious trouble.
有一次上美術課
We were supposed to draw a picture.
隨便我們畫什麽
Anything we wanted.
我畫了一個人
I drew a man.
另一人拿螺絲起子刺他脖子
He got hurt in the neck by another man with a screwdriver.
你在電視看到的嗎?
You saw that on TV, Cole?
老師很生氣
Everyone got upset.
他們找媽媽開會
They had a meeting.
媽媽開始哭
Mom started crying.
後來我就不畫這些了
I don't draw like that anymore.
你現在畫什麽?
How do you draw now?
微笑的人們
I draw... people smiling,
奔跑的狗兒
dogs running,
還有彩虹
rainbows.
畫彩虹不會惹上麻煩
They don't have meetings about rainbows.
沒錯 我想是不會
No. I guess they don't.
我現在在想什麽?
What am I thinking now?
我不知道你在想什麽
I don't know what you're thinking now.
我在想...
I was thinking...
你人很好
you're nice,
但是你幫不了我
but you can't help me.
我以爲你說的是另一家餐廳
I thought you meant the other Italian restaurant I asked you to marry me in.
安娜 對不起
I'm so sorry, Anna.
我最近老是忘了時間
I just can't seem to keep track of time.
今天的訪談也不太順利
And I didn't have a very good session today.
他們倆非常相似
They're both so similar.
相同的動作和表情 也有同樣的心理問題
The same mannerisms, same expressions, same things hanging over their head.
他可能有受到虐待
I think it might be some kind of abuse.
科爾的手上有抓痕
Cole has... scratches on his arm.
好像是被指甲抓傷
I think they might be fingernail cuts.
也許是抗拒時抓傷的 我不知道
Defensive cuts, maybe. I don't know.
可能是老師或鄰居
Maybe a teacher or a neighbor.
應該不是他母親 我看過他們相處 看起來不像是她
I don't think it's the mother. I've seen her with him, and it doesn't seem to fit.
我也可能看錯
Or I could just be wrong.
也許他只是很喜歡爬樹
Maybe he's just a kid who likes to climb trees a lot.
安娜
Anna.
我知道我疏遠了你
I know that I've been a little distant, all right?
我知道你很生氣
I know that it makes you mad. I just...
但我覺得這是我彌補的機會 我不想錯失它
feel like I'm being given a second chance, and I don't want it to slip away.
安娜
Anna.
結婚紀念日快樂
Happy anniversary.
別一直看我
Stop looking at me.
我不喜歡被人這樣看
I don't like when people look at me like that.
我都跟湯米·唐一起上學
I walk this way to school with Tommy Tammisimo.
他是你的好朋友?
Is he your best buddy?
他討厭我
He hates me.
你也討厭他?
Do you hate him?
不
No.
這是你媽媽安排的?
Did your mom set that up?
對
Yes.
你跟她說過湯米的事嗎?
Did you ever talk to your mom about how things are with Tommy?
- 我什麽都不跟她說 - 爲什麽?
- I don't tell her things. - Why not?
我不希望她像別人那樣看我
'Cause she doesn't look at me like everybody else, and I don't want her to.
- 我不想讓她知道 - 知道什麽?
- I don't want her to know. - Know what?
我是個怪胎
That I'm a freak.
嘿
Hey.
你不是怪胎 好嗎?
You are not a freak. Okay?
別相信別人說的話 那全是屁話
Don't you believe anybody that tries to convince you of that. That's bullshit.
你不必相信這種話
You don't have to go through your life believing that.
好嗎?
Okay?
走吧
Come on.
- 你說了髒話 - 我知道 對不起
- You said the "S" word. - Yeah, I know. Sorry.
你爸跟收費站小姐
So your dad lives in Pittsburgh with a lady...
住在一起?
that works in a toll booth?
她工作時尿急怎麽辦?
I wonder if she has to pee when she's working.
她會忍住嗎?
Think she just holds it?
我不知道 我也在想這問題
I don't know. I was just thinking about that myself.
今天你一直問起我爸
You asked a lot of questions about Dad today.
爲什麽?
How come?
有時我們會做些事引人注意
Well, sometimes we do things to draw attention,
以表達我們對某些事的感覺
to express our feelings about certain issues...
像離婚之類的事
divorce, whatever.
就像有些人會故意丟東西 讓人找到
For example, a person might leave something on the desk for someone else to find.
你知道自由聯想書寫法嗎?
Do you know what free association writing is, Cole?
不知道
No.
自由聯想書寫法就是拿支筆
Free association writing is when you take a pencil in your hand,
在一張紙上開始寫字
and you put the pencil to a piece of paper and you start writing.
不去看或是想你在寫什麽
And you don't look at what you're writing or think about what you're writing.
只是不停地寫
You just keep your hand moving.
你的手只要不停下來 過一陣子...
And after a while, if you keep your hand moving long enough,
那些你從不知道的思路會浮現出來
words and thoughts start coming out that you didn't even know you had in you.
也許是... 你在別處聽到的事
It could be something you heard somewhere else,
或是藏在你內心深處的事
or feelings you had deep inside of you.
你寫過嗎? "不讓嬰兒安靜我就宰了你"
Have you ever done any free association writing, Cole?
寫過
Yes.
你都寫些什麽?
What did you write?
令人不安的事
Upset words.
在你爸離開前 你寫過那些事嗎?
Did you ever write any upset words before your father left?
我不記得了
I don't remember.
幫我個忙 好嗎?
Can you do something for me?
想想對于我們的訪談 你要什麽結果
I want you to think about what you wanna get out of our time together...
訂個目標
what our goal should be.
我要什麽?
Something I want?
如果你能改變你的人生
If you could change something in your life, anything at all,
你要改變什麽?
what would it be?
我能不能不要什麽?
Instead of something I want, can it be something I don't want?
可以
Okay.
我不要再感到害怕
I don't want to be scared anymore.
"傷痕可能是自殘的結果"
你去開門好嗎?
You gonna get that?
你去開門好不好?
Are you gonna get that?
- 你好-你好
- Hi. - Hi.
- 你在店裏沒看夠我嗎? - 我正要去...
- Don't you see enough of me at the store? - Yeah, I'm on my way out...
亞美希人的跳蚤市場
to the flea market in the Amish country.
我想請你一起去
I thought maybe you'd wanna come along...
順便教我挑貨
and show me how to buy at one of these things.
我今天不想跟亞美希人打交道
I don't know if I can deal with the Amish today.
他們不准別人罵髒話吐口水
You can't curse or spit or anything around them.
我以爲你想出去走走
I just figured maybe you'd just want to get out and get some air,
最近你有點沮喪
because you've seemed kind of down lately.
我沒事
Um, I'm okay.
我回來時可以過來把東西帶給你看
Do you think that maybe I should stop by on the way back, show you what I got?
不會很麻煩的
Because that wouldn't be a problem.
不用了 禮拜一再說
No, l... You know, I can see on Monday.
好吧 沒關系
Sure, yeah, that's fiine. I'm just...
那我走了 回頭再談
Okay, so I guess I'm gonna get going then. I'll speak to you later.
- 別踩到馬糞了 - 多謝關心
- Don't step in the horse manure. - Thank you very much.
臭小子 快走吧
Keep moving, cheese dick.
"我不會再打人"
有沒有人能告訴我 1790到1800年間
Can anybody guess what city was capital of the United States of America...
美國首都在哪裏?
from 1790 to 1800?
給你們一個提示 是你們住的城市
I'll give you a hint: It's the city you live in.
- 費城 - 沒錯
Philadelphia! - Right, right.
費城是美國最古老的城市之一
Philadelphia's one of the oldest cities in this country.
很多人終其一生待在這
A lot of generations have lived here and died here.
這裏的每個地方幾乎都有悠久曆史
Almost anyplace you go in this city has a history and a story behind it.
包括這所學校和校園
Even this school and the grounds it sits on.
有沒有人能告訴我 一百年前這所學校是什麽?
Can anyone guess what this building was used for a hundred years ago...
在你來上學之前 甚至在我來這兒上學之前
before you went to school here, before I went to this school even?
科爾 你說
Yes, Cole.
他們以前在這兒吊死人
They used to hang people here.
不對 你從哪兒聽來的?
No, uh, that... Mm-mm. That's not correct. Where'd you hear that?
他們把哭喊的犯人拉開
They pulled the people in, crying and kissing their families bye.
旁觀者向他們吐口水
People watching... spit at them.
科爾 這裏以前是法院
Uh, Cole, this building was a legal courthouse.
很多法律在這裏制定通過
Laws were passed here... some of the very first laws of this country.
當時這兒都是律師 議員
This whole building was full of, uh, lawyers,
- 立法者 - 他們也吊死犯人
- lawmakers. - They were the ones that hanged everybody.
呃
Uh...
我不知道是誰跟你說的 但是...
I don't know which one of these guys told you that,
他們不過是想嚇唬你
but, uh, they were just trying to scare you.
我不喜歡別人這樣看我
I don't like people looking at me like that.
怎樣看你?
Like what?
別看了
Stop it!
我不知道該怎麽看
I, uh, l-l-I don't know how else to look.
你是結巴史丹利
You're Stuttering Stanley!
- 什麽? - 你在上學時講話都會結巴
- Excuse me? - You talked funny when you went to school here.
一直到高中都還這樣
You talked funny all the way to high school.
- 什麽? - 別這樣看人 這樣對方會很難受
- What? - You shouldn't look at people. It makes them feel bad.
- 你怎麽... - 別再看著我了
- How did you... - Stop looking at me!
是...是誰告訴你的?
Who have you... Been speaking to?
結巴史丹利 結巴史丹利...
Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!
- 別說了 - 結巴史丹利
- Stop it. St-St-St... - Stuttering Stanley!
- Stop that! - Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!
結巴史丹利...
Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!
住嘴 你... 你這怪胎
Shut up, you f-f-freak!
嗨 大人物
Hey, big guy.
你好嗎?
How's it goin'?
我現在什麽都不想談
I don't wanna talk about anything right now.
好吧
Okay.
你喜歡魔術嗎?
You like magic?
恩
Hmm?
仔細看 神奇的銅板
Observe: The magic penny.
看起來很普通
Looks like an ordinary penny.
但我只要搖一下
But I do my little magic shake, and...
它就會跑到右手裏
now it's in my right hand.
不過把戲還沒有完
But that's not the end of the magic trick.
我只要再搖一下
I do another little shake, and...
它就會跑到口袋裏
right there in the vest pocket.
不過這也還沒有完
But that's not the end of the magic trick.
我再搖一下
I do another little shake...
然後
and...
它又回到左手來了
right back in the left hand where it started.
這不是魔術
That isn't magic.
什麽意思?當然是魔術
What are you talking about? Of course it's magic.
銅板一直都在你的左手
You just kept the penny in that hand the whole time.
是嗎?
Think so?
我不知道你也會搞笑
I didn't know you were funny.
馬爾科姆 給我坐下來聽好
Malcolm, sit your cute butt down and listen up.
實際上 安娜就像我的姐妹
No doubt about it. Anna is like my sister.
你最好讓她快樂
And you better make her happy. I'm not talkin'about no...
不只是表面上的快樂而已
"Mmm, this taste like real butter"kind of happy.
我說的是...
I'm talkin' about... What's up, girl?
像"真善美"的茱麗安德魯絲
"Julie Andrews twirling around like...
在山頂上跳舞一樣那麽快樂
a mental patient on a mountaintop" kind of happy.
我說的是這種快樂
That's the kind of happy I'm talkin'about.
過來
Shh. Come here.
別跟她說是我說的
Don't tell her I told you,
她說她第一次在街上見到你
but she said she knew she love you...
她就知道她愛你
from the first time she met you on the street.
她願意爲你付出一切
She'd do anything for you.
我愛你們
I love you guys.
我哭慘了...
My nose is running. Turn it...
"抗憂郁劑 日服二次"
只要輕輕搖一下
And then you do the magic shake.
銅板就會從我口袋...
The penny has moved from my pocket...
跑到原來的手裏
all the way back to the hand it started in.
真無聊
That's stupid.
這應該很好笑的
It's supposed to be funny.
蠢斃了 把銅板還我
It's stupid. I want my penny back.
他很少被人邀請 這是我們的榮幸
He doesn't get invited places, so it's our pleasure.
他上次參加聚會已是一年前的事
Last time was a Chuck E. Cheese party a year ago.
他躲在玩具隧道裏不肯出來
He hid in one of those purple plastic tunnels and didn't come out.
- 在什麽地方? - 是一間兒童餐廳 小孩去的地方
- Chucky who? - Cheese. It's a kids place.
- 借過 - 抱歉
- Excuse me. - Sorry.
外面有人嗎?
Is someone out there?
請開這扇門
Open this door, please. Come on.
我沒法呼吸 你聽見了就開門吧
I can't breathe. If you can hear me, open this door.
我發誓我沒偷主人的馬匹
I swear on my life I didn't take the master's horse.
快開門 否則我破門而出把你扼斃
Open this door, or I'll break through it and grab you!
- 廣告明星都有自己的休息室 - 用來幹嘛?
- The star of the commercial always gets his own trailer. - For what?
用來單獨思考角色與對白
He needs a place to think about his character, alone.
你只有一句台詞
You only had one line.
達倫 快看
Derrick, check it out.
我爸逼我邀請他的
Oh, yeah. My dad made me invite him.
生日快樂 達倫
Happy birthday, Derrick.
你想進去嗎?
Is there somethin' you want to see in there?
不
No.
我們要演一部戲
We're gonna put on a pretend play.
- 你想加入嗎? - 好
- Wanna be in it? - Okay.
劇名是"地窖裏有誰"?
It's called "Locked in the Dungeon."
你就演被關在地窖裏的角色
Yes, Cole, and, uh, you get to be the one locked in the dungeon.
不
Don't! Don't! Don't! Don't!
不要...
Don't!
Let me out! No! No!
不!不!
No! No!
科爾?
- Cole?
Cole!
這門的鑰匙在哪?
Is there a key for this door?
科爾?聽得見我嗎?
Cole? Honey? Honey, can you hear me?
科爾...天啊!
Oh, my God! Cole!
救救我!救命啊!
Help me! Help! Help! Help!
他沒有心髒病
The tests would indicate he did not have a seizure.
他很好
He's doing fiine.
休息一下就可以回家了
After some rest, he can go home tonight.
你兒子身上有些瘀青和傷痕
There's some cuts and bruises on your son...
- 我很擔心 - 糟了
- that are concerning me. - Oh, man.
那是運動造成的
Yeah, those are from sports.
你以爲是我弄的?
You think I hurt my child?
你想我是個壞母親?
You think I'm a bad mother?
史隆太太就在那裏 她是醫院社工人員
Mrs. Sloan over there, she's a social worker with the hospital.
她會問你一些手續上的問題
She's gonna ask you a couple procedural questions.
我孩子今天怎麽了?
What happened to my child today?
他出事了 出事了 事情很不對勁
Something was happening to him, physically happening. Something was very wrong!
嗨
Hey.
你父親睡前會說故事嗎?
Did your father used to tell you bedtime stories?
很久以前 有一個王子
Once upon a time there was this young prince,
他決定要開車兜風
and he decided that he wanted to go for a drive.
他找來他的司機 他們就開始出發
He got his driver, and they started driving.
開著 開著
Driving, driving.
開了很久的車
Driving a lot.And, uh,
他們開太久 他睡著了...
they drove so much that he fell asleep.
當他醒來...
And...
他發現他們還在開車
Then he woke up, and he realized they were still driving.
- 這旅程真長 - 克勞醫生?
- This was a very long trip. - Dr. Crowe?
你以前根本沒說過睡前故事
You haven't told bedtime stories before.
我是沒說過
Uh, not too many, no.
你得加點劇情進去
You have to add some twists and stuff.
好 加點劇情
Okay. Some twists.
哪種劇情?給我點提示吧
Like what kind of twists? Give me an example.
- 也許他們沒油了 - 他們沒油?
- Maybe they run out of gas. - They run out of gas?
沒油 很好 他們在開車嘛
That's good, 'cause they're driving, right? Okay, so...
告訴我你爲何憂傷?
Tell me the story about why you're sad.
你覺得我很憂傷?
You think I'm sad?
你怎會這麽想?
What makes you think that?
你的眼神告訴我的
Your eyes told me.
我不該談這個的
Not supposed to talk about stuff like that.
以前有個叫馬爾科姆·克勞的人
Once upon a time, there was this person named Malcolm.
他幫小孩解決問題
He worked with children.
他喜歡這份工作
He loved it.
他愛這工作甚于一切
He loved it more than anything else.
有一天...
And then one night, he found out that...
他發現他錯待了一個孩子
he made a mistake with one of them.
他幫不了那個孩子
He couldn't help that one.
他自責不已
And he can't stop thinking about it.
無法忘懷
He can't forget.
從那時起 一切都改變了
Ever since then, things have been different.
他不再是以前的他了
He's not the same person that he used to be.
他太太
And his wife...
不喜歡現在的他
doesn't like the person that he's become.
他們不再交談 像陌生人一樣
They barely speak anymore. They're like strangers.
有一天 馬爾科姆遇見了一個小孩
And then one day, Malcolm meets this wonderful little boy.
一個很棒的小孩
A really cool little boy.
這小孩跟那孩子很像
Reminds him a lot of the other one.
馬爾科姆決定要幫助這小孩
And Malcolm decides to try and help this new boy...
因爲他覺得如果能幫得了這個小孩
'cause he feels that if he can help this new boy,
那就等于是... 救了先前的那個小孩
it will be like... helping that other one too.
這故事有什麽結局?
How does the story end?
我不知道
I don't know.
現在我要跟你說我的秘密
I wanna tell you my secret now.
好
Okay.
我可以看見死人
I see dead people.
在夢裏嗎?
In your dreams?
在你醒著的時候?
While you're awake?
在棺材裏的死人嗎?
Dead people, like, in graves, in coffins?
他們像我們一樣走來走去
Walking around like regular people.
互相看不見對方
They don't see each other.
他們只看得到他們想看到的
They only see what they wanna see.
他們不知道自己已經死了
They don't know they're dead.
你多常見到他們?
How often do you see them?
每時每刻
All the time.
到處都有他們
They're everywhere.
你不會跟別人說吧?
You won't tell anyone my secret, right?
不會 我保證
No. I promise.
等我睡著再走 好嗎?
Will you stay here until I fall asleep?
當然好
Of course.
科爾...他的病情比我想的嚴重
Cole has pathologies more severe than initially assessed.
他會産生幻覺
He's suffering from visual hallucinations,
有妄想症
paranoia,
還有某種學齡兒童的精神分裂症
Some kind of... school-age schizophrenia.
也許必須住院服藥
Medication, hospitalization may be required.
我也幫不了他
And I'm not helping him.
我是席琳恩 科爾的媽媽
Hi, this is Lynn Sear, Cole's mom.
我想跟你談談你兒子和他的朋友
Yeah, uh, l... I'd like to talk to you...
叫他們別再碰我的兒子...
about your boy and his friends keeping their goddamn hands off my son.
媽媽?
Mama?
不行 晚飯還沒煮好
No, dinner is not ready!
你想怎樣?
What are you gonna do?
你不能再傷害我了
You can't hurt me anymore!
蘭尼 你是個壞老公
Neddy! You're a terrible husband, Neddy!
我是被你逼死的 蘭尼
Look what you made me do! Neddy!
從前有個男孩
Once there was a boy,
一個與衆不同的男孩
very different from all the other boys.
他住在叢林裏
He lived in the jungle,
他能跟動物交談
and he could speak to the animals.
你覺得這出戲很遜嗎?
Did you think the play sucked big time?
什麽?
What?
湯米·唐演過咳嗽藥廣告
Tommy Tammisimo acted in a cough syrup commercial.
他說大家都演得很不自然
He said everyone was self-conscious and unrealistic.
還說這出戲遜斃了
He said the play sucked big time.
這個湯米好像很討人厭
This Tommy kid sounds like a real punk.
我覺得這出戲很好看 比"貓"還棒
I thought the play was excellent. Better than "Cats."
- "貓"? - 算了
- "Cats"? - Never mind.
你在醫院裏說的話很有意思
Cole, I was really interested in what you told me at the hospital.
我想再多聽一些
I'd like to hear more about it.
科爾
Cole?
怎麽了?
What?
那裏有什麽嗎?
Is something up there?
科爾
Cole,
我什麽也沒看見
I don't see anything.
不要動
Be real still.
有時你會有種感覺
Sometimes you feel it inside,
好像墜入萬丈深淵
like you're falling down real fast,
但你其實根本沒動
but you're really just standing still.
你會不會突然覺得頸背寒毛直豎?
You ever feel the prickly things on the back of your neck?
會
Yes.
全身上下都起雞皮疙瘩?
And the tiny hairs on your arm, you know, when they stand up?
會
Yes.
那就是他們
That's them.
當他們生氣
When they get mad,
就會變得很冷
it gets cold.
我沒看到 你確定他們真的在嗎?
I don't see anything. Are you sure they're there?
科爾
Cole?
請你叫他們走開
Please make them leave.
我正在努力
I'm workin' on it.
走吧
Come on.
爸 媽
Mommy, Daddy?
我的喉嚨好疼
My throat hurts.
跑!快跑!
Run! Run!
小兒止咳糖漿
Pedia Ease cough suppressant.
- 藥力溫和 有效... - 科爾
- Gentle, fast, effect... - Cole.
不管他們怎麽說 暖氣壞了
I don't care what they say, this thing is broken.
把手套脫掉
Take 'em off.
別放在餐桌上
I don't want them on my table.
我在打掃時看了你的抽屜
I saw what was in your bureau drawer when I was cleaning.
你要不要坦白一下?
Got something you want to confess?
你爲何老是拿走那只墜子?
Hmm? The bumblebee pendant? Why do you keep taking it?
那是外婆的
It was Grandma's.
要是摔壞了你知道我會怎樣
You know, what if it broke? You know how sad I'd be.
你會哭 因爲你很想念外婆
You'd cry 'cause you miss Grandma so much.
沒錯
That's right.
人們有時以爲失去了什麽
Sometimes people think they lose things,
其實沒有 只是被換了個地方
and they really didn't lose them... it just gets moved.
是你把那墜子換了個地方的嗎?
So, did you move the bumblebee pendant?
不要生氣
Don't get mad.
這次是誰拿走的?
So, who moved it this time?
也許有人跑進來 把墜子從我抽屜拿走
Maybe someone came in our house, took the bumblebee pendant out of my closet...
再放進你的抽屜
and placed it nicely in your drawer.
- 也許是 - 我很累了 科爾
- Maybe. - God, I am so tired, Cole.
我的身心都很疲倦 我的心靈也累了
I'm tired in my body, I'm tired in my mind,
我的心靈也累了
I'm... tired in my heart.
我需要幫忙
I need some help.
我們家的狀況不是很好
You know, I don't know if you noticed, but our little family isn't doing so good.
我一直在禱告
I mean, I've been praying,
也許是我禱告的方法不對
but I must not be praying right.
現在我們只能自求多福
Looks like we're just gonna have to answer each other's prayers.
我們無法坦白就無法撐下去
If we can't talk to each other, we're not gonna make it.
老實告訴我 寶貝 我不會生氣的
Now, tell me, baby. I won't get mad, honey.
墜子是不是你拿的?
Did you take the bumblebee pendant?
不是
No.
你吃夠了 馬上離開餐桌
You've had enough roast beef. You need to leave the table.
快點
Go!
快來 我帶你看我爸藏的槍
Hey, come on. I'll show you where my dad keeps his gun. Come on.
狗狗 來吧
Sebastian, come on!
媽媽
- Mama?
如果你的氣消了
If you're not very mad,
我今晚能不能跟你一起睡?
can I sleep in your bed tonight?
看著我
Look at my face.
我沒有生氣
I'm not very mad.
寶貝 你爲什麽發抖?
- Baby, why are you shaking?
科爾 怎麽了?
Cole, what's wrong?
神啊 求求你告訴我
Oh, God, please tell me!
求求你
Oh, please.
這是愛德華時期的 鑲工細致 鑲滿了細鑽...
It's Edwardian, beautifully worked...
和一顆緬甸藍寶石
with mine-cut diamonds and an actual color Burmese sapphire.
經典之作
It's timeless.
你...
You, uh...
有沒有普通一點的鑽戒?
Got anything a little plainer?
普通一點? 你想用個普通的鑽戒 來配你那普通的老婆 對吧?
Plainer? You want a plain ring to go with your plain fiance? Is that how it is?
不是啦 寶貝 別生氣
No! Baby, don't get in a tissy.
你太美了
Uh... You're so beautiful.
你就像緬甸藍寶石一樣美
You're like a Burmese sapphire all by yourself.
- 你根本不需要這些 - 嗯嗯
- You don't need all that. - Uh-huh.
爲什麽不先試戴一下
Why don't you try it on...
看看你們覺得怎樣?
and see how you both feel about it.
怎麽樣?
There. How does that feel?
這枚鑽戒代表一種渴望
I think this piece, um, communicates a longing.
曾經擁有這枚鑽戒的女主人
I imagine that the woman who owned it...
有過一段刻骨銘心的戀情
Ioved a man that she couldn't be with.
她是卷發和棕色眼睛嗎?
Did he have wavy hair and chestnut eyes?
- 呃 - 我不知道
- Huh? - Um, I don't know, but...
這裏有許多首飾都能和主人溝通
a lot of the pieces in this store communicate,
你們應該挑個合適的
and I think you should choose a piece that speaks to you.
當人們死後 他們所擁有過的東西
I think maybe when people own things and then they pass away,
上面都會留下他們的痕迹
a part of themselves gets printed on those things,
就像...是指紋
like... like fingerprints.
我幫你們包起來
I'll just wrap it up.
你不需要一個碩士
You don't need a guy with a Master's.
你需要個虎臂熊腰的壯漢
You need a wrestler with a neck larger than his head.
不 我需要有碩士學位的壯漢
No, I need a wrestler with a Master's.
這是什麽? 生日快樂
- What's this? - Happy birthday.
- 你送的? - 嗯
- For me? - Mm-hmm.
這是... 初版書
It's a... first edition.
哇哦
Wow.
- 你一定花了不少錢 - 不 我從你的年終獎金上扣下來
- You know, this is too much. - No. Took it out of your Christmas bonus.
太棒了 安娜
It's perfect, Anna.
謝謝
- Thanks.
你最想要什麽?
What do you want more than anything?
我不知道
I don't know.
我說過我想要什麽
I've told you what I want.
我知道我想要什麽
I know what I want.
跟我老婆再度交談
I want to be able to talk to my wife again.
就跟以前一樣
The way we used to talk to each other.
回到兩人世界
Like there was no one else in the world except us.
你要怎麽做?
How are you gonna do that?
我不能再當你的醫生了
Can't be your doctor anymore.
我沒有關懷自己的家人
I haven't paid enough attention to my family.
這樣是不對的
Bad things happen when you do that.
你懂嗎?
Do you understand?
- 我會幫你介紹... - 別放棄我
- I'm going to transfer you. I know two psychologists. - Don't fail me.
別放棄我 你是唯一能幫助我的人
Don't give up. You're the only one who can help me, I know it.
我幫不了你
I can't help you.
你說過...
You...
會有別人來幫你的
Someone else can help you.
你相信我 對吧?
You believe me, right?
克勞醫生 你相信我的秘密吧?
Dr. Crowe, you believe my secret, right?
我不知道該怎麽回答
I don't know how to answer that, Cole.
你如果不相信我的話
How can you help me...
你怎麽能夠幫我?
if you don't believe me?
有些魔術是真的
Some magic's real.
人獨處時爲什麽會害怕?
Do you know why you're afraid when you're alone?
我知道 我知道
I do. I do.
抱歉讓你等這麽久 文森
I'm sorry, Vincent. I hope I didn't leave you alone too long.
這裏好冷
Whew. It's cold in here.
文森 你怎麽哭了?
Vincent, why are you crying?
你不會相信我的
You won't believe.
抱歉讓你等這麽久 文森
Sorry, Vincent. I hope I didn't leave you alone too long.
這裏好冷
Whew. It's cold in here.
文森...
Vincent...
這裏好冷
Whew. It's cold in here.
知道嗎 我也不喜歡針筒
Nah, you know what? I never liked him either.
我小時候有一次驗血
When I was a kid, I had this blood test done,
我吐了護士一身
and I threw up chili cheese fries all over this male nurse.
抱歉 李醫生在 2 線
Excuse me. Dr. Reed is on line two.
我得聽這個電話
Vincent, will you excuse me? I have to take this.
等我一下
Just give me a minute, okay?
我不想死
Yo no quiero morir.
- 我的天啊 - 我不想死
- Oh, my God. - Yo no quiero morir!
你最近很忙?
You been running around?
這樣比較好過?
Make you feel better?
我喜歡忙碌 那樣很好
I like to run around. It's good exercise.
想問我問題?
Do you want to ask me questions now?
想加入陸戰隊第七師嗎?
Want to be a lance corporal in Company "M, " Third Battalion, Seventh Marines?
我們剛被派往越南打仗
We're being dispatched into the Quang Nam province.
待會吧
Maybe later.
有事發生了 對嗎?
Something happened, didn't it?
你嚇壞了?
You wigging out?
是的 我想是吧
Yes. I think I am.
知道這話什麽意思嗎?
Do you know what "Yo no quiero morir" means?
西班牙文 意思是"我不想死"
It's Spanish. It means "I don't want to die."
你覺得那些鬼魂爲什麽找上你?
What do you think these ghosts want when they talk to you?
你想一想
I want you to think about it, Cole.
仔細地想一想
I want you to think about it really carefully.
你想他們想幹嘛?
What do you think they want?
要我幫忙 對 我也這麽想
- Just help. - That's right. That's what I think too.
他們想要你幫忙
They just want help, even the scary ones.
我想我知道該怎麽讓他們走開
I think I might know a way to make them go away.
怎麽做?
How?
傾聽他們
Listen to them.
如果他們不想要我幫忙呢?
What if they don't want help?
萬一他們只是想傷害別人呢?
What if they're just angry and they just want to hurt somebody?
我想應該不會
I don't think that's the way it works.
你怎能確定?
How do you know for sure?
我並不確定
I don't.
嗨
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
怎麽回事?
What's happening?
科爾
Go!
你怎麽了?
What's happening to you?
有人傷害你? 我去揍扁他們
Is someone hurting you? I'll kick their ass.
科爾 要是他們傷害你...
Cole, if they're hurting you...
媽媽 你睡吧
Mama, you sleep now.
我覺得好多了
I'm feeling much better now.
你是不是想告訴我什麽?
Do you want to tell me something?
她跑了大老遠才找到我 對吧?
She came a long way to visit me, didn't she?
我想是的
I guess she did.
去拿杯水吧
Can you get some water?
那是她妹妹
That's her sister.
我父親癌症過世時我就經曆過了
You know, when I went through this with my father's cancer...
但這孩子臥病在床兩年
I just can't imagine a child being in bed for two years.
看過多少醫生?
How many... How many doctors?
- 我想有六個了 - 六個不同的醫生都...
- I think it was six. - Six different doctors?
我想是的
I think so, yes.
我剛聽說... 小的那個現在也病了
I just heard the, uh, little one is falling ill now.
願上帝幫助他們
God help them.
別離開 好嗎?
Don't go home, okay?
我不會的
I definitely won't.
恩
Aah!
先生?
Mister?
抱歉 先生
Excuse me, mister.
你是琪拉的爸爸嗎?
Are you Kyra's daddy?
這是給你的
It's for you.
她有事想告訴你
Sh-She wanted to tell you something.
不 他來了 正朝我走過來呢
Oh, no, here he comes. He's coming my way. Psst!
想跳舞嗎?
Would you like to dance?
我跟朋友一起來的
Well, actually, I just came with my friends.
怎麽樣?
Oh, well, how about this?
我們先跳一下
We can dance for a little bit,
我要是跳不好 你可以踢我
and if you don't like the way I dance, you can kick me.
好吧
Oh, okay then.
該吃午餐了
It's time for lunch, Kyra.
我覺得好多了-很好啊
I'm feeling much better now. - That's so great, honey.
你該吃飯了
It's time for your food.
我吃完以後可以出去玩嗎?
Can I go outside if I eat this?
你下午的情況一向都不好
I don't know. You know how you get sick in the afternoons.
再說吧
We'll see.
別說吃起來很奇怪 我不想聽你那麽說
Don't say that it tastes funny. You know I don't like to hear that.
山姆他媽媽打電話來了
Tami's mom called.
是你害她一直都病著
You were keeping her sick.
她說你喜歡它
You liked it, she said.
她會保護你的
She looked out for you.
琪拉會回來嗎?
Is Kyra coming back?
再也不會了
Not anymore.
好 化好了
I think that's enough. That's enough makeup.
好的
Okay.
- 該你上場了 - 我們得快點
- They're calling for the stable boy. - We have to hurry!
你剛剛跟誰說話?
Who, uh... Who were you talking to?
我是在練習台詞
Just practicing my lines.
謝謝你給我這個機會
Thanks for giving me this part, Mr. Cunningham.
很久以前 這劇院發生過一次大火
You know, when I went to school here, there was a terrible fire in this section of the theater.
他們重建了這裏
They rebuilt the whole thing.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
只有心無邪念的人 才能拔出石中劍
Only he who is pure of heart can take the sword from the stone.
讓那孩子試試
Let the boy try.
但他只是個清掃馬廄的男孩
He is a stable boy. He cleans up after the horses.
安靜 無知的村民
- Silence, village idiot.
讓那孩子走向前
Let the boy step forward.
亞瑟王萬歲
Hail, King Arthur!
耶
Yea!
你演得很棒
I thought you were really great in the play, Cole.
- 真的? - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
- 知道嗎... - 什麽?
- You know what else? - What?
我覺得湯米·唐很遜
I thought Tommy Tammisimo sucked big time.
我有辦法讓你妻子聽你說話
I got an idea how you can talk to your wife.
趁她熟睡時跟她說話
Wait till she's asleep.
她會不知不覺的把你的話聽進去
Then she'll listen to you and she won't even know it.
我不會再見到你了吧?
I'm not gonna see you anymore, am I?
我想我們該談的都已經談過了
I think we said everything we needed to say.
也許該跟你的親人談一談了
Maybe it's time to say things to someone closer to you.
也許我們可以假裝明天還要見面
Maybe we can pretend like we're gonna see each other tomorrow.
只是假裝
Just for pretend.
好的
Okay.
我要走了
I'm gonna go now.
明天見 科爾
I'll see you tomorrow, Cole.
我沒事 警察先生
I'm okay, Officer.I-I'm okay.
我不知道是怎麽回事
I don't know what happened.
天啊 希望沒有人受傷
Geez, I hope nobody got hurt.
你很安靜
You're very quiet.
你在氣我沒趕上你的演出
You're mad I missed the play, aren't you?
我得做兩份工作
I have two jobs, baby.
這對我們非常重要
You know how important they are for us.
我真的很想到場
I'd give anything to have been there.
我現在可以跟你溝通了
I'm ready to communicate with you now.
溝通?
Communicate?
告訴你我的秘密
Tell you my secrets.
是什麽?
What is it?
不知道前面發生了什麽事故?
You know the accident up there?
什麽
Yeah.
有人受傷了
Someone got hurt.
真的?
They did?
是一位女士
A lady.
她死了
She died.
天啊 你看得到她?
Oh, my God. What, you can see her?
對 她在哪裏?
- Yes. - Where is she?
就站在我的車窗旁邊
Standing next to my window.
你嚇壞我了
Cole, you're scaring me.
他們有時也嚇壞我了
They scare me too sometimes.
他們?
They?
鬼魂
Ghosts.
你看得見鬼魂?
You see ghosts, Cole?
他們要我幫忙
They want me to do things for them.
他們跟你說話?
They... They talk to you?
他們要你做事?
They tell you to do things?
以前就是他們嚇壞了我
They're the ones that used to hurt me.
媽媽 你在想什麽?
What are you thinking, Mama?
你以爲我是怪胎? 看著我
- You think I'm a freak? - Look at my face.
我絕不會認爲你是怪胎 永遠不會
I would never think that about you. Ever.
- 懂了嗎? - 懂了
- Got it? - Got it.
讓我想一下
Just let me think for a minute.
外婆跟你問好
Grandma says hi.
她說她很抱歉拿走墜子
She says she's sorry for taking the bumblebee pendant.
她太喜歡它了
She just likes it a lot.
什麽? 外婆有時會來看我
- What? - Grandma comes to visit me sometimes.
科爾 這樣是不對的
Cole, that's very wrong.
- 你知道外婆已經過世了 - 我知道
- Grandma's gone, you know that. - I know.
- 她要我... - 別說了
- She wanted me to tell you... - Cole, please stop.
她要我告訴你 她去看你跳舞
She wanted me to tell you she saw you dance.
她說你小的時候...
She said when you were little,
跟她吵過一次架
you and her had a fight...
就在你舞蹈表演之前
right before your dance recital.
你以爲她不想看你跳舞
You thought she didn't come to see you dance.
她去看了
She did.
她躲在後面 你沒看到她
She hid in the back so you wouldn't see.
她說你像個天使
Sh-She said you were like an angel.
她說...
She said...
你曾經到她的墓地去
you came to the place where they buried her,
問了她一個問題
asked her a question.
她說答案是...
She said the answer is...
每一天
every day.
你問了她什麽?
What did you ask?
我...
Do...
有沒有讓她感到驕傲?
Do I make her proud?
媽媽
Mama.
大家好 你們都知道 我...
Hi, everybody. As most of you know,
我並不習慣這樣
I'm not used to doing this,
我也答應安娜不會令她困窘
and I promised Anna that I'd try not to embarrass her.
這任務就交給她母親吧
I'll leave that to her mother.
我們想謝謝大家的出席
But we do want to thank all of you for coming...
並與我們分享這美妙的日子
and for sharing this wonderful day with us.
我心中既苦又樂
It's bittersweet almost, for me,
因爲我並不想把她交出去
'cause I hate giving her up.
安娜
Anna?
我好想你
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you too.
爲什麽 馬爾科姆?
Why, Malcolm?
什麽?
What?
- 什麽... - 你爲何離我而去?
- What is it? - Why did you leave me?
我並未離你而去
I didn't leave you.
我看得見死人
I see people.
他們不知道自己已經死了
They don't know they're dead.
- 你多常見到他們? - 每時每刻
- How often do you see them? - All the time.
到處都有他們
They're everywhere.
他們只看得到他們想看的
They only see what they want to see.
好了 麥克
Okay, Mikey.
等等 讓我想一下
Come on. Give me a minute.
天啊
Oh, God.
- 不是很痛 - 讓我看看
- It doesn't even hurt. - Let me see.
讓我看看 把手拿開
Let me see. Put your hand...
天啊
Oh, God.
好的
Okay.
我想我沒事 真的
I think I'm okay. Really, I think it just went...
我想子彈並沒有留在裏面
went in and out.
根本不會痛
It doesn't even hurt anymore.
我想我現在可以走了
I think I can go now.
我只是需要做幾件事
I just needed to do a couple things.
我得幫助一個人
I needed to help someone.
我想我做到了
I think I did.
我也要告訴你一些事
And I needed to tell you something.
你對我一直都是最重要的
You were never second.
永遠都是
Ever.
我愛你
I love you.
好好睡吧
You sleep now.
明早開始一切都會改觀的
Everything will be different in the morning.
晚安 馬爾科姆
Good night, Malcolm.
晚安 親愛的
Good night, sweetheart.